Andrey Chasovskikh

Telephone: +7 921 321 5519

E-mail: <u>andrey.chasovskikh@gmail.com</u>

Website: http://andreycha.info
Location: St.Petersburg, Russia

Visa status: non-EU citizen, visa is required

Profile

I'm a software developer with 7 years of experience in the area. My experience includes development of both frontend and backend applications, with a bias to backend development: financial software, ETL solutions, medical information systems, and mobile applications.

Skills

Programming languages: C#, Java, Delphi, Pascal

Technologies: .NET, WinForms, WPF, Silverlight, LINQ, ADO.NET, PLINQ, async/await,

T-SQL, XML, Windows Phone, Smart GWT, DevExpress, Infragistics

Databases: MS SQL Server

IDE: MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, NetBeans, Borland Delphi

VCS: TFS, git (basics), Subversion
Bugtracking: TFS, Jira, Gemini, Redmine
CI: TeamCity, Cruise Control

Additional tools: MSTest, xUnit, JUnit, ReSharper, memory and performance profilers

Languages: Russian (native), English (working proficiency)

Other: OOP, multithreaded and asynchronous programming, test driven

development, clean code, agile methodologies, code review

Professional experience

Broadridge Financial Solutions (Paladyne Systems before Sept. 2011), St. Petersburg, Russia. March 2011 – present

Current position: senior software developer (since August 2014)

- Taking part in developing new product for reference data quality and arbitration, which consists of a document storage and a number of services:
 - integrated with Security Master product: loading and keeping up-to-date 10+ mln entities
 - developed a number of input and output adapters for data transformation engine, made a lot of improvements based on real usage
 - implemented apply/diff algorithm for document storage
 - bugfixing and adding various features across the application
- Took part in developing and supporting application for managing securities reference data, Security
 Master. This included estimating, designing and developing features (from UI to backend code and
 database), supporting existing functionality, writing tests (mostly employing TDD) and technical
 documentation, code review, solving client issues. Developed major features for a number of
 releases:
 - designed and developed 'Custom Dictionaries' feature
 - helped to keep a client by developing custom FormPF solution
 - took part in developing 'Auto-Failover' feature
 - took part in high-level design of 'Custom Calculated Fields' feature, developed it from scratch
- Took part in supporting complementary product for loading reference data from vendors into other products, ETL Manager, which is written in Java. Mentored two new developers for 6 months.

Keywords: C#, Java, Powershell, T-SQL, Infragistics, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, MS SQL Server, IIS, Tomcat, TFS, git, Jira, TeamCity, TDD, RhinoMock, NSubstitute, Mockito, Scrum

BrainSystems, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2010 - March 2011

Position: software developer

- Helped to win a client by developing e-archive system prototype: full application design and development.
- Took part in developing Java web application for medical municipal institution, both front-end and backend parts.

Keywords: C#, Silverlight, Entity Framework, WCF RIA Services, MS SQL Server, Java, Smart GWT, Oracle, Jasper Reports, JBoss, NetBeans, SVN, Redmine

Kostasoft, St. Petersburg, Russia. September 2008 - September 2010

Position: software developer

- Took part in developing and supporting medical information system, Avicenna.NET. This included writing new functionality (from UI to backend code), supporting existing codebase and writing technical documentation.
- Streamlined development process by initiating weekly sprints and product backlog.
- Improved knowledge sharing across the team by leading weekly retrospective meetings.

Keywords: C#, T-SQL, DevExpress, MS Visual Studio, MS SQL Server, SVN, Gemini

Academic experience

St. Petersburg Polytechnical University. February 2010 – February 2014

Have lead exercises and several lectures for "Databases" course (MS SQL Server, T-SQL) every spring semester.

Education

2010 - 2012, St. Petersburg Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Postgraduate student (unfinished).

2004 - 2010, St. Petersburg Polytechnical University

Faculty of Engineering Cybernetics, Information and Control Systems department. Specialist degree in Software Engineering. GPA: 4.5/5.0.

Talks & publications

- "async/await: avoiding common mistakes", .NEXT Moscow, December 2014
- "Windows Phone applications security", HackInParis, June 2013
- "Inspection of Windows Phone applications", BlackHat Abu Dhabi, December 2012
- "Clustering algorithms overview", http://web-analitik.info/, September 2010

Certificates & diplomas

- 3rd prize at "VK.com messenger for Windows Phone" contest (2012)
- MCTS: Windows Application Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4 (2011)
- Brainbench C# 3.0 Fundamentals Master (2011)
- Microsoft IT Case Cup semifinalist diploma (2011)
- Exigen Services' ".NET Workshop", letter of archievement (2009)